Today I'm joined by former CIA officer and
whistle-blower uh John Kiriakou and I'm hosting
him live here in our studio in Nicosia (CYPRUS). A
great honor and we're going to have a conversation
which is going to be split into two parts. The
first part will be on the geopolitical reality
surrounding our region here in the Eastern
Mediterranean. And the second part will be
uh how well do you know John part. I'm gonna
try and do my best and ask him questions that he
hasn't been asked by all these other podcasters uh
he's been going to. So John welcome. Good good to
see you. John, regarding the situation around us,
Americans are being told that there is a ceasefire
with Iran and talks happening, but are we actually
looking at um isolated conflicts or is it a single
war unfolding across uh multiple fronts? Oh, I
think very strongly that it's a single war. Israel
thrives in regional chaos. It always has. It is
stronger when Iraq is in chaos, Libya is in chaos,
Lebanon and Syria are in chaos, and now Iran is in
chaos. Uh the the Israelis couldn't bring down the
America the uh the American that's a Freudian
slip. They couldn't bring down the Iranian
government by themselves. So they enlisted the
help of the United States after something like
six consecutive presidents refused to do it.
this one finally agreed. So, I think that it's
all part of the same big conflict and it's drawn
in a lot of disinterested parties. For example,
the Kuwaitis have no no desire to be in the
midst of a of a conflict, nor the Bahrainis,
the Emiratis, the Qataris, the Omanis, certainly
because they're the middlemen between the United
States and Iran. Uh even the Saudis, the Lebanese
have seen enough war for two generations and yet
here they are all embroiled in armed conflict
because the US and Israel decided to attack Iran.
True. Now there are growing concerns that the Iran
war has already consumed significant portions of
America's missile stockpiles. Is the US becoming
overextended? And um what does that mean if the
conflict escalates further? I do think that the US
is overextended not just recently. This goes back
to last year when Israel began, you remember the
Israelis began by by launching missiles at Iranian
military sites. The Iranians responded by sending
waves of slow motion drones. The the Iranians
were were practicing something we were calling
strategic patience where they're hit by missiles
because of public opinion. They have to respond.
So they respond by sending 600 700 drones. They
call the Israelis through the Jordanians and say,
"We're responding by sending drones just so that
they don't raise the stakes." And the Iron Dome
is able to shoot almost every drone down. I think
seven got through, which was valuable intelligence
for the Iranians for later. But then the Israelis
attacked again. And then the Americans said,
"We're going to help the Israelis protect
themselves." and sent Patriot missile batteries.
And then the Iranians responded again. Well,
a couple of the Iranian missiles got through.
Again, valuable intelligence that the Iron Dome
is not all that it's cracked up to be. The Iranian
response was always far less than what the Israeli
action u that required a response uh was. And
the Iranians really really hoped that this would
just go away. In the end, Donald Trump dropped a
30,000 pound bomb and uh in his words, obliterated
the Iranian nuclear program back in June 20 25
years ago. Correct. Well, if it's obliterated,
then we're done. It's finished. We win. But of
course, the Israelis didn't like that because they
need chaos in order to feel safe. And so when the
Iranian government did not collapse, the Iranian
people did not take to the streets to overthrow
their government or to hang the Ayatollah from
a a a light pole or something like that. The
Israelis panicked and then Benjamin Netanyahu came
repeatedly to the United States and succeeded in
convincing Donald Trump that this needed to be a
larger scale war. Mhm. But what about the concerns
about America having an issue with its missile
stockpile? Yeah. Well, the conventional wisdom
in Washington was that the reason the conflict
didn't continue last year is because we were
out of Patriot missiles. We're just out of them.
And then when we began moving naval assets
to the region to carrier strike forces,
we had enough missiles to protect them, but not
to protect them and supply the Israelis. And so
in places like Huntsville, Alabama, and Western
Pennsylvania, and wherever these missiles are
made, they went into overdrive to to try to make
up the missile gap. Well, I don't think anybody
in the administration expected this conflict
to be ongoing now in May of 2026, and we just
can't produce these missiles quickly enough.
Okay. So, basically, it's um if the conflict
u picks up again, then America has a problem.
Yeah, I think America has a problem. Yeah. And
I think we're right on the edge of that problem in
a big way. What happens if what happens if there's
another anti-American attack that has nothing to
do with with Iran? How do we protect ourselves?
I don't know if they've thought of that, but
anyway, see, but this is the thing. The United
States has never been able to fight a two-front
war. We should have learned that lesson the hard
way when we were in both Afghanistan and Iraq. We
can't fight two wars at the same time. And that's
when we were at maximum production levels.
We are not at maximum production levels now.
And that now there's an energy shortage on top of
it. Who would have predicted that, right? I mean,
everybody would have predicted. The intelligence
analysts, I'm sure, predicted that, but I don't
know if Trump he heeds to No, he doesn't. In fact,
a 60 Minutes reporter asked him a few weeks ago,
uh, who are your closest adviserss? And he said,
I have no advisers. I go with my gut. But his gut
is frequently wrong. And he comes to decisions
based on arrogance rather than on intelligence.
There's not an intelligence officer in Washington
who would have told Donald Trump that the Iranian
regime would collapse with the launch of the first
missile. Nobody believed that. So why did Trump?
Because the Israelis told him that that would
be the case. Yeah. And that's why you have the
the big reshuffleling in the leaders of the armed
forces in the US, right? You know, that's a very
interesting event unfolding. So there are two
there are two rumors going around Washington.
One is that many of these senior military leaders,
you're talking about the Secretary of the Navy,
the chairman and vice chairman of the Joint
Chiefs of Staff. The rumor is on one hand
that many of them were opposed to the war in the
first place. I can tell you from my own personal
experience that's probably true because when we
were attacking Iraq, the Joint Chiefs of Staff
were adamant that we not get involved in that war.
They're always the last ones who want to commit
troops. Yeah. The last ones because they know
what war is. It's the politicians who want the
war. It's the State Department hawks because they
don't have to fight it. They just have to watch it
being fought. On the other hand, another rumor is
that very simply Donald Trump loves turnover. You
have to be 1,000% pro-Trump and proTrump policy
to keep your job. General Kaine, the chairman of
the Joint Chiefs, is solidly strongly proTrump.
He was Donald Trump's deputy CIA director in
the first term. Uh, and there are others who are
not blindly proTrump. And as it turns out, their
careers don't last. Now, I want us to briefly
touch upon Yemen briefly. It is central to this
conflict. Yeah. Most Americans have no idea about
it, but it's not their fault, right? Um sitting at
the Bab el Mandeeb Strait, one of the world's most
critical critical shipping choke points connecting
the Red Sea with the Mediterranean. How does
Yemen's position, if you can just briefly tell
the American viewers, how does it change its
Yemen's position change the regional picture
in ways Washington isn't fully explaining to
its citizens? Yeah, that's a good question. So,
if you can picture the the Horn of Africa in the
east and the Arabian Peninsula, it comes almost
to a close at the Bab el Mandib. The Babel Mandab
is only something like 9 miles across or 16 miles
across. It's very, very, very close. And so all
shipping coming through the the Swiss canal has to
eventually pass through the Bab al Mandab before
it goes out into the Arabian Sea. Thus the problem
with Somali pirates in in previous decades. Um
I've spent a lot of time in Yemen over the years,
a lot. I've been to Yemen five times and every
time I go it's worse than the previous time. Worse
in what way? The first time I went to Yemen, um,
they were they were declaring unity. There used
to be two Yemens, the Yemen Arab Republic and the
People's Democratic Republic of Yemen. And they
joined together to form Yemen. Okay. The People's
Democratic Republic was a Soviet satellite state.
The Soviet Union fell apart. They joined together
in one Yemen. People were literally dancing in the
streets. That was the first time I've ever seen
that in my life. People were literally dancing
in the streets. And um and then the second time I
went, the economy was failing. People were saying
h this unity thing didn't work out the way we're
we thought it was going to be. The third time
I went, they were firing Scud missiles at each
other. Yeah. And everybody was predicting they're
going to split into two Yemens again. They didn't
split into two Yemens. Something worse happened.
So, the Civil War broke out. The the fourth time
I went, um, I got in a taxi at the airport to go
to the hotel and I said to the taxi driver,
"So, how are things in Yemen?" And he said,
"They're not bad. Uh, it's just that the Houthis
are flying Scuds against us." I'm sorry, not the
Houthies. Um, he said, "The Saudis are flying,
not Scuds, flying drones against us and they're
firing from drones." And I said I I chuckled
and I said, "The Saudis don't have drones. This
is 2009." And I thought, "Oh, but we do. We're
involved in a war in Yemen, and it's undeclared.
And our drones are based right there in Djibouti,
which is just 16 miles away." So I thought, "Oh,
the American people don't know we're involved in a
war in Yemen." And I reported it to John Kerry. I
was the uh the investigator on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee at the time. The last time I
went to Yemen, 2011, it was so dangerous that they
picked me up in an armored convoy at the airport.
You're only allowed to stay at the Marriott.
It has 30 foot blast walls all the way around
it. And then the day after I arrived, there was an
attack on a group of South Korean diplomats on the
road from the airport to the Marriott. All six of
them were killed. At the end of the week, a group
of South Korean intelligence officers arrived to
investigate the attack and they were attacked and
killed. And then the South Koreans just closed
their embassy. Well, Yemen's Houthi rebels have
essentially taken over control of the government.
They don't really control the country. They just
control a part of the country that includes the
capital city. They are Shia Muslim. They're the
minority in Yemen and they are close to the
Iranian government. So the conventional wisdom
is that the Iranians are arming them. That's
likely true. And the Houthis have expressed
solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza. And so the
Houthis have been doing several things. They have
been harassing shipping coming through the Babel
Mandeb. They've been firing on the uh the vessels,
including American military vessels, which is
a really really stupid thing to do. And then
um they've been launching um missiles into
southern uh Israel. They haven't done much
damage. They they hit Akaba's small airport once
and um they injured a couple people. They may have
killed a guy in Hifa, something like that.
But it's more harassment than anything else.
The Israelis responded and surprised everybody
with this response by opening diplomatic relations
with a breakaway republic called Somaliand. I've
been to Somali land. The only country who have
done that in the world, right? The only country
in the world to recognize Somali land as an
independent [clears throat] country. So I went to
Somaliand in 2009. It's the northernmost state in
Somalia. Somalia, of course, is a failed state. It
doesn't have a central government. and it doesn't
have a leader, not one that's recognized. It
doesn't have a foreign policy. It's just anarchy,
chaos. Somali land can actually function
on its own. It can't feed its people,
but it can function on a day-to-day basis. So,
the Israelis have offered diplomatic recognition
in exchange for the Somali landers offering
the Israelis a military base. And they're
going to use that base to attack the Houthis.
So, but also control the Bab el Mandeeb. Well,
that's the that's the whole key. Yeah. Entry and
exit of it. Right. That's the whole key. If you
if you can beat up on the Houthis, then the Bab el
Mandeeb remains open. Have they built their base?
No, not yet. It's going to take a little time.
Now, I want us to shift to but it still has to
do with all the dynamics in the area. What have
you your views on the re recent flotilla raid by
Israeli in international waters far from Israel
but right off the coast of Greece still though
it's international waters but it's close to the
coast of Greece where the arrested participants
the participants were arrested and they were
made to walk through Crete all the way to the
airport I don't know if you've seen images
I haven't seen the images now yes yes so the
Israeli army effectively operating inside Greece
what does that say about Greece's compliance and
sovereignty. I'll show you the images. I'm very
disturbed by this. Yeah. You and I were talking
off offline yesterday about this this new and
very strong relationship between Greece uh Greece,
Cyprus and Israel. Yeah. Over lunch. Yeah. I
totally get it because Turkey's a common enemy.
There's a lot of economic development at play.
A lot a lot of natural gas. I get it. But then
at the same time, you see these examples where
it's like the countries are are losing their
sovereignty. They're beholdened to the Israelis
and the Israelis act like they own the place.
I was surprised when I flew into Cypress the
other day and I I happened to look at the arrivals
board because I wanted to see where to pick up my
luggage and it said Tel Aviv, Tel Aviv, Tel Aviv,
Tel Aviv, Athens. Yeah. So, it's true. Things have
changed in the Eastern Mediterranean. But this
this thing, sorry to answer your question about
about Kriti (Crete), this is utterly completely
unacceptable. The Israelis have no authority
to operate inside Greek territory or Cypriot
territory unless the governments of Greece and
Cyprus are conceding that authority and allowing
them to do it. In which case, shame on them.
Okay. Strong message, clear, loud and clear. Now,
Trump and his family, there are claims,
I'm going to say claims so that I don't get
um um what say a lawsuit my way. There are
claims circulating that members of the Trump
family have deep business ties with defense and
drone technology companies alongside reports of
a sharp rise in their personal wealth uh net worth
in the 15 months that Trump has been officially in
office. What's your take on these claims, John,
and how should viewers interpret them? Sure. Um
I I I would go beyond calling them claims.
I think that they've been they've been borne
out. Um but but this is the difference between
what the American government used to look like
and what it looks like today. The Constitution
is very clear, Susie. It it's that the American
government is three co-equal branches. The
executive, the legislative, and the judicial.
Over the course of the last two generations,
the legislative has weakened itself.
um on purpose and has seated that authority,
that constitutionally granted authority to the
executive. Donald Trump maintained in his first
term that a sitting president can do literally
anything he wants and not be prosecuted for it.
That was absurd to most of us. And it went all
the way to the Supreme Court and the Supreme Court
ruled in Trump's favor. And so now what? You want
to do insider trading? No problem. You want to
be a grifter? Go ahead and do it. No problem.
You want to make money on drones or crypto or real
estate in the occupied territories? Nobody's going
to stop you because the Supreme Court said you
could. And so we see these reports that Donald
Trump's children are involved in high-end real
estate deals, billions of dollars in real estate.
They're involved in creating new cryptocurrency.
They're involved in in um uh drone technology and
and sitting on the board of directors of drone
companies. Yeah. And they're getting rich rich
rich. And apparently, according to the Supreme
Court, there's nothing illegal about that. It
makes us a far weaker country. Last week I hosted
uh Dimitri Lascaris and he's You've heard of him?
Oh, I follow him every single day. Great. Yeah.
And my partner, after I I mentioned him to you
like a month or so ago, it was independently of
my of my partner. She uh she's been following
him because he's been driving all over Iran and
reporting from the, you know, on the ground from
Iran. Um, but yeah, I only know him because of
you. Um, he is a Greek American investigative
journalist. He was a lawyer, class action lawsuit
lawyer, extremely successful. and 10 years ago he
said, you know, he had done what he was going
to do and he's a very very good investigative
journalist, always on the ground. [snorts] Uh I
think he visited Iran five times so far and he's
gone multiple times south Lebanon. Anyway, he
had spent 10 days uh inside Iran during the war
in March, traveling across the country from north
uh the Kurdish part all the way down to uh Minab
where the deadly uh school um uh thing happened
and even uh spent time in the Strait of Hormuz on
on a boat. And then he spent five days in Lebanon
a day after the eternal darkness operation took
place reporting those five days from Beirut and
from South Lebanon reaching Nabatieh. Now what
stood out for me is that he described a sometimes
he he stood up for me that he mentioned is that
he described a reality very different from
what western audiences are told about Iran
and the existence of um other religious groups.
He said that Jewish and Christian communities are
practicing freely in Iran. They are not living
under oppression. Were you aware of that? Yes,
you were aware of that. Oh yeah. Yeah. In fact,
uh Iran hosts one of the longest continuously
operating Christian churches on the planet. It's
it goes back to something like the fifth century,
the sixth century. It's one of the oldest anywhere
ever. And um I wasn't aware of that. Oh yeah.
They've got a thriving Christian community in
Iran. And there's also a small Jewish community
uh and they're perfectly free to practice
their religion. Specifically on on Iran's
Jewish community, what the other thing that stood
out for me is that you know Tehran still hosts
uh the um they say it's one of the oldest
Jewish populations in the world. Might be
small but it's significant. It's one of the
oldest Jewish populations in the world. And
their synagogue in Tehran um the main one was
as you know struck by the IDF. Mhm. And the IDF
described it as collateral damage with almost no
western coverage on on the matter. But this gives
the Israelis the opportunity to say there's not
even a place for Iranian Jews to to worship. Yeah,
cuz you bombed it. You bombed it. But my question
is why the silence when it happens? Why the
silence? But when it happens the other way around,
if if Iran had bombed a synagogue in Europe,
what do you think the global reaction would
have been there? Oh, world war. Seriously? Oh,
yes. Yeah, it would have been world war. See, but
the thing is is religious freedom doesn't fit into
the western narrative on Iran. The the the Western
countries don't want people to believe that there
is freedom of religion in Iran. And there is,
you know, Iran I read this just recently. Iran
is is probably only about 55 or 60% Shia Muslim.
It's seen as the world's largest bastion of Shia
Islam. But in fact, there are so many different
ethnic groups and so many different faiths that
sure while it is the majority, it's barely the
majority because there are still Zoroastrians,
a lot of Zoroastrians, there are Sunni Muslims,
especially in what in ihe Gulf we used to call
Arabistan along the southwest coast. Okay. and in
Baluchistan. So it's kind of like a hook that goes
to the east of the border with Pakistan.
Um there are Jews, there are Christians,
the Kurdish also they're Sunnis, right? The
Kurds, the Kurds are also Sunnis. Mhm. Okay.
And now I want us to touch upon my fatherland.
You know, it's a very sensitive topic for me,
Lebanon. So South Lebanon, despite what's being
called the ceasefire, villages are still being
uh systematically destroyed and levelled through
controlled detonations. Israel control controls
a so-called uh yellow zone which spans 7 to 10
kilometers inside Lebanon and they've deemed any
person now during the ceasefire people are trying
to return back to South Lebanon. Any person who
enters the so-called yellow zone is branded by
Israel as a terrorist. We're talking residents of
those villages and they're immediately um killed.
So we're seeing daily footage coming out. It's
all on X and it's mostly coming up from Israeli
accounts and the IDF documenting the scale of the
demolitions and the levelling of of villages.
We're talking it's around a thousand homes
a day. I read somewhere and there are reports
which Dimitri confirmed to me that um the these
demolitions are being incentivized by the Israeli
government. I mean they're getting paid for
according to number of homes they detonate or they
demolish with their bulldozers on a daily basis.
And alongside that, there's the footage that
they're also using white phosphorus again,
which is a chemical weapon not allowed. Um, so the
'Gazification' of South Lebanon is in full effect.
Um, what's your assessment of what's happening
on the ground in South Lebanon? The so-called
ceasefire isn't in effect, and people need to know
that. Yeah, just because Donald Trump declares
that there's a ceasefire does not mean that the
Israelis are going to stop firing at anybody. Uh,
I think that the Israeli goal is to make it a a
dead zone, a no man's land. Not to settle it. I
think eventually eventually to settle it, but
right now they they want to ethnically cleanse
the whole of southern Lebanon. I heard something
the other day from a friend of mine at the White
House who who has told me things that have come
to pass. Like he's told me in advance, he told me
a week in advance, we're going to attack Iran
next week. And then when I said on a podcast,
I have a friend who's in the know who said we're
going to attack Iran. People jumped all over me.
I saw one of the comments, one of the comments I
saw on YouTube was this guy wants us to think that
somebody just walked up to him, a convicted
criminal, and told him defense secrets. And
I said, "Yeah." And that's exactly what happened.
And a week later, we attacked Iran. Yeah. Yeah. So
he told me that the administration is working
with the Israelis to create something called
uh the dead zone. Oh. Or dead zones in southern
Lebanon. It's a combination of the area around
the Iranian uh nuclear uh area. Yeah. where where
the experimentation the the uranium enrichment was
taking place and in southern Lebanon where the
policy will be if anything moves in those areas
it's going to be bombed and killed. They're
already enforcing it. I think it's going to
be an actual policy for the whole of southern
Lebanon. They're calling it the yellow zone now.
Yeah. Yeah. Nothing will be able to live there.
The Lebanese Ministry of Health has published a
report that since May 2, when they started their
war with Lebanon, the toll has reached around
2,550 Lebanese killed civilians mostly and lots
of members of the press and paramedics. They do
this double, triple, and quadruple tap strikes
and 7,800 wounded. And that adds on top to the
thousand uh casualties that we registered from the
November 24 ceasefire which they also never kept
in effect. And they continue to bomb with missiles
and use white phosphorus. I I heard a statistic
just two days ago uh on the BBC that the Israelis
have killed more journalists since October than
were killed in World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq
and Afghanistan. Iraq and Afghanistan combined.
I saw it. The BBC, you're right. It's true. It's
true. Their goal. And I was on a debate um on the
Pierce Morgan show a couple of months ago and
I was there with Danny Ayalon from the Mossad,
uh Alan Dersowitz, the attorney of Jeffrey
Epste. You had good company. the the great
thinker uh Scott Horton and uh and Pierce and me
and I did the least amount of speaking. The rest
of them mostly just screamed at each other. And I
said uh at the end Pierce said to me, um, "Do you
believe that Hamas is a terrorist organization?"
He still keeps asking that question. And I said,
"I believe that for the most part Hamas is a
is a national liberation organization." I said,
"As it as it goes to attacking civilians,
specifically planning to attack civilians,
yes, of course, that's an act of terror." Agreed.
Agreed. So, do you believe October um October 7th
was a terrorist uh attack? I said, "Again, if the
intent was specifically to to kill civilians, yes,
it was an attack, a terrorist attack." And he
said, "Then why are you disagreeing with Danny
Ayalon and Alan Dersowitz?" And I said, "Pierce,
the policy can't be kill everybody. That's not a
policy. That's a genocide." And that's what the
Israelis have decided to do. They're committing
genocide in Gaza, genocide in in southern Lebanon,
genocide in the West Bank, genocide in Iran, and
we can't abide it. you cannot have as a policy to
just kill everybody. He called me later and told
me that I was responsible for changing his mind on
this war in uh in Gaza and southern Lebanon. Well,
let's hope he sticks to this change of mind. I
hope so because he also said that someone else
had changed um bas and then he's gone back to his
old ways. So, yeah, he does. Yeah. It's like he
can't help himself. Yeah. Yeah. Can't believe
we discussed Piers Morgan on in our in our talk
here. But I I have to make it a point that South
Lebanon is has a striking feature. It's not just
strategically important with the Litani River,
which is the largest the largest uh natural water
source of the Middle East. This is more important
than oil. People think Oh, it's much more
important than oil. And that's why the Israelis
are so interested in it. Uh-huh. Uh-huh. Yeah.
But also south Lebanon is religiously significant.
There are some of the oldest these are some of the
oldest Christian dance villages deeply connected
to the Bible to early Christianity right and
to the teachings of Jesus. They are levelling
churches and religious sites and um cemeteries.
The tomb of St. Peter that that was not now but it
was in the 2024 uh part of the war. You know, this
is a I'm going to say something that's going to be
unpopular. You're probably going to get some angry
uh angry responses, but I blame I blame American
evangelical Christians for this. I believe that
much of American-based evangelical Christianity
is a cult. It's not a religion. It's a cult.
And they're constantly trying to recruit people
into their cult. And as a result, they've allied
themselves with Zionist Israel at the expense of
the original Christians. The original Christians
in the region, the Palestinian Christians, the
Lebanese Christians, and others around the region,
I don't think they care at all about Christianity.
I think it's all about their own diluted view of
Zionism and of the apocalypse. If you if you
speak one-on-one with an American evangelical,
not all evangelicals, but these Zionist ones,
they will tell you that they that they're close to
Israel because they want all Jews around the world
to return or to return to go to move to Israel to
hasten the return of Christ. Because when all
the Jews, according to the book of Revelation,
when all the Jews return, that's when the Messiah
comes and everybody lives happily ever after
following the World War, the apocalypse. Yeah,
it's all nonsense, of course, but everybody else
has to pay the price. How many thousands, maybe
hundreds of thousands have died over the years
because of this stupid cultlike belief that they
can force the hand of God. True. Now, I'm shifting
to 2028. I got to ask you all these questions
because I have you here, [laughter] you know,
and I want your views on all these matters.
So 2028 crucial not just for America but for
for the whole world and the region here if we're
still standing that is. So who do you think the
Democrats are most likely to you know push forward
as their nominee? Same goes for the Republicans.
Yeah. Well the Republicans are easier. The the
conventional wisdom is that it's going to be JD
Vance. I don't think it's going to be JD Vance. I
think it's going to be Marco Rubio. JD Vance is a
child. The guy just turned 40 like two weeks ago.
He's not equipped to run for president. He's no
Barack Obama. Not that I'm pro Obama. I'm strongly
anti-Obama, okay? But he's just not equipped.
He was in the Senate for two years. Two years.
That's the that's the extent of his involvement
in government. Two years in the Senate, during
which time he did literally nothing. And so
now he's running for president. Donald Trump has
tried to sort of uh school him. That's not really
working out. Marco Rubio has already run for
president. He's a very long-time senator. He was
a congressman before that. He's been a successful
attorney and investment banker. Um and this whole
idea, Susie, of MAGA, make America great again.
It's it's on the downswing. uh it had its time
just like the Tea Party had its time in the first
decade of the century and the Republican party
is returning to the party of neoconservatism.
Well, Marco Rubio is a neoconservative and he's
not going to rest until the Cuban government
is overthrown. It was his idea to overthrow
Nicholas Maduro in Venezuela. It was his idea to
recommend to Donald Trump that we go along with
the Israeli demand to attack Iran. He loves these
wars. He thrives on these wars and he has Lindsey
Graham whispering in his ear that these wars are
good for America somehow. So I don't think it's
going to be JD Vance. Plus, like I say, he's got
40 more years ahead of him. He He has plenty of
time. It'll be Marco Rubio. The Democrats
are far far more difficult. Gavin Newsome.
I think he's so easily attacked. I don't think
he can make it through a long primary season.
Let me explain something and please forgive the
uh the length of my response to you. In 1972,
George McGovern was the Democratic nominee
for president. He lost 49 of the 50 states.
Okay? And the Democratic National Committee, the
DNC, said, "We will never allow that to happen
again." And so they instituted this policy in the
Democratic primaries called superdelegates. So,
if you are an elected official, a Democrat, you're
a governor, a senator, a congressman, the head
of a a state party, the deputy head of a state
party, a guy that I like, a guy that, you know,
I owe a favor to, you become a superdelegate. So,
in your home state, you get to vote on the nominee
for for president. Yeah. It doesn't matter who
wins in your state. And I'll give you an example.
There were two states in 2016 where Bernie Sanders
got 60% and Hillary Clinton got 40%. And Hillary
Clinton won every single one of the delegates.
How is that a democracy? Because the superdelegate
overrides the choice. Yeah. Yeah. That's not
democracy. That's not democracy. The Republicans
don't have that. The Republicans, whoever wins the
primary is the nominee. The Democrats, they choose
their person in the smoke filled back room like
the olden days. That's the nominee. I don't think
Gavin Newsome has that kind of support within the
Democratic structure, but he's also very easily
attacked. Gas right now is between $8 and $9 a
gallon in um California. Well, why when it's $45
a gallon everywhere else in the country? because
the taxes are so high Yeah. that it's $9. Um,
California lost 2 million residents. Yeah. Between
the last census and the census before. That's two
congressional delegate uh congressional districts.
People are running away from California. They're
moving to Arizona, Texas, Oklahoma, Florida,
Florida because taxes are too high. Yeah. And
so there's another thing about him too. Gavin
Newsome was a member of the San Francisco City
Council. Then he was the chairman of the city
council. Then he was the mayor of San Francisco.
Then the lieutenant governor of California. Then
the governor of California. Okay. So he's this is
a very wellthought-out plan to move higher higher
higher and become president. When he was running
for governor of California, he asked his lifelong
best friend, who was also his campaign manager,
to represent him at a political function. The
man did. It wasn't because Newsome was busy. It
was because Newsome was having an affair with his
best friend's wife and they got caught. What kind
of person is that? If if your best friend and your
own wife can't trust you, yeah, why am I supposed
to trust you? Are you gonna screw me behind your
back as an American taxpayer? So, I don't I don't
like or trust Gavin Newsome at all. But the
thing is is who's the alternative to Newsome?
um JB Pritsker, who's the the governor of um
Illinois, is trying to break out of the pack,
but um he's Jewish. He's a well-known Zionist, and
people are saying that's not going to work out so
well having a Jewish nominee. Um another
one is the the governor of Pennsylvania,
Josh Shapiro. Josh Shapiro is a is a veteran
of the IDF. Okay. He's an American citizen who
served but he didn't serve in the US military. He
went and joined the Israeli military. So sorry, no
IDF soldier is getting my vote to be president of
the United to be president of the United States.
It's outrageous. Then you have Kamala Harris who's
making noise about running again. Kamala Harris,
she couldn't get elected to the local school
board, let alone to get herself elected. Nobody
wanted her to be the Democratic nominee for
president. I'd be surprised if her own if her
own husband voted for her. Uh, and then you
and I were talking about this app earlier,
Kelshi. It's a predictive app, and you you bet
money on, you know, is it going to rain in Nicosia
today? Yes. No. And it gives you odds. Well,
if you look at who's going to be the Democratic
nominee for president, and I looked an hour
ago, okay, there are 46 people listed. They're
in trouble. The Democratic Party. My other part of
the question is do you think there's a possibility
this time for a serious third candidate to emerge
something like what Ross Perot and Ron Paul tried
um to do but with much stronger momentum John
this time from Americans on both sides who
are feeling increasingly disconnected from the
system. They've had it with with the uniparty
system. It's a uniparty. It is a uni party and
it has been for a long time. Would you like such
uh very very much to rise? Okay. So again,
forgive the long- windedness of my of my response,
but you know, as recently as a hundred years ago,
we had multiple viable third parties in the United
States. We had a we had a viable socialist
party. We had a viable progressive party. Um,
in 2016 I travelled to 12 states with the nominee
of the Libertarian Party, Governor Gary Johnson,
the former Republican governor of New Mexico. And
because Trump and Clinton were both so unpopular,
he was running as a Libertarian. Uh, uh, Jill
Stein was running as the Green Party nominee.
And there was an independent, and his name escapes
me now. He was a former CIA officer running as an
independent. Um, and everybody believed that they
had an honest shot at winning something. Governor
Johnson said to me, "We were campaigning in Utah
and he said, "The polls are showing we have a
real shot at winning Utah and New Mexico. Can you
write an op-ed in the Washington Post?" I said,
"Of course." So, I wrote this op-ed about how
we intended to win these two states with the
idea being that you pull the eventual of the
eventual winner below 270 what is it 270 yeah
um electoral votes so that the vote goes into
the House of Representatives. Of course, the
the nominee who came closest would probably win,
but it might it might be an event to encourage the
growth of third parties. So, we did well in Utah.
We got like 11%. The polls showed us at 23. Um,
but Trump won most of the states. Clinton won the
remaining states and the third parties didn't win
anything. In the end, the libertarians got 3%
which was a historic high. Okay. With that said,
you compared you compared what might be in
2028 with with Ron Paul and Ross Perot and
I'm going to add John Anderson. John Anderson
was a liberal Republican congressman. No such
thing exists anymore. A liberal Republican
congressman from Illinois in 1980. He ran
against Ronald Reagan and Jimmy Carter. And
in the end, Reagan got 51%. Um Carter got
41% and Anderson got 7%. Anderson had no money.
Wow. And he got 7% of the national vote. Well,
Ron Paul got under 2% when he ran. Ross Perot
got a good 20%. But he also spent, you know,
almost a billion dollars out of his own pocket.
This year could be different. This year could
be different because if you look at the polls,
yeah, people hate the uni-party for all intents
and purposes. The Democrats and the Republicans
are just different sides of the same coin. They
essentially agree on everything. There are minor
disagreements around the edges that they want us
to think are grave differences. And they're not.
Yeah. They're the same. Yeah. And so if you look
at the polls, somebody like Tucker Carlson Yes.
has an actual shot at winning this thing. So,
yeah, I spoke to him about this recently. Okay.
And he professes to not be interested. I Glenn
Greenwald is another popular writer, podcaster,
commentator. I know that Glenn has spoken to
him as well. It's like, you have to run. And I
and I told Tucker a week ago, I said, "You have
to run and I'm all in." and he said, 'Well, no,
it's yeah, I'm not a politician. Which is true,
but that's exactly what America wants. They don't
want a politician. They want someone they can
trust. And out of everybody that's out there in
the chattering class like you and me, he's the one
that people trust the most because he says what
he believes even at a significant personal cost.
He has to have security now. He has to he has to
have security because he's becoming so prominent,
so important. He's he's getting threats and we're
in this crazy period right now. Three different
people have tried to kill Donald Trump. He said
that his family members have received threats.
Absolutely. Yeah. And he decides to run. It's it's
going to really set his life in danger. Direct
danger. So maybe that's what he's contemplating.
I think that's exactly what he's contemplating. I
think that that is I think that his primary uh
concern is his family. Yeah. As it should be.
And I think that he's probably thinking, "What
do I get out of this? I get one headache after
another." Yeah. He likes his life. He lives in a
in a beautiful part of the country. He's an avid
fly fisherman, so he can go fishing anytime
he wants. Why change that? Is it really worth
it? You know, when I was traveling with Governor
Johnson, I asked him why the libertarians weren't
catching on. Because libertarian philosophy is
very attractive to me. Ronald Reagan once said,
"Government is the problem. It's not the solution
to the problem." That's in in a in a sentence,
that's the philosophy of the Libertarian Party.
And he said, "We're not catching on because we
don't have a benefactor. We don't have somebody
who can write a check for $150 million and,
you know, put us on the map." AIPAC would
never support and AIPAC would never ever ever
support a libertarian candidate for president.
Never. Because we're anti-militarist. And so,
um, there was one wealthy man in California. I
never knew his name. I never learned his name.
He was described to me as the canned tomato king
of California. This is how he made his money. And
he gave us $40,000. And so we used it to buy a
motor home, a Winnebago. And we drove from state
to state to state campaigning. And then when we
lost the election, we just sold the Winnebago.
So yeah, it's it's all about the money. Yeah,
you need at least a billion dollars to run for
president. Now Obama was the first one to raise
a billion. This last time both the Democrats and
Republicans raised one and a half billion. Crazy.
Yeah. So nobody else can compete. I want to end it
coming back to our region here. Um and um and end
it on asking you on what what is your opinion on
the future of NATO, especially considering Israel
repeatedly threatening Turkey primarily through
its former prime minister Naftali Bennett, you
know, spewing out threats at Turkeykey's necks.
Oh yeah, that's going to be the big final war.
Oh yeah, everybody's talking about it. But we
all know that with the US in NATO and Article
5 in place, yes, Israel cannot realistically
go to war with Turkey and go it alone. So what's
your view of your projection? They want that war
with Turkey. They do. They're actively seeking
war with Turkey. Turkey is their last impediment
to them um realizing their greater Israel dream.
Yes. So what's your projection? How is that going
to happen with the US in NATO? Is the US going
to stay in it? Just your projection. I mean,
you know, putting There are a lot of moving parts
in this situation. I happened to have dinner
recently with a with a Turkish deputy minister.
He was in Washington. Oh. And reached out to me.
I have I had never met the man before. Okay. And
we ended up having dinner together. And I asked
him exactly this question. Yeah. What did he say?
He said, "We welcome an Israeli attack on Turkey.
God has help us here in Cypress. We're going
to seriously cuz Cyprus is stuck right in the
center of it. Oh yeah. And you know all hell
is going to break loose and 38% of our land
is already occupied by the Turkish. That's right.
38% 40,000 soldiers stationed. That's right. They
are unloading uh on a daily basis since February
28th at the port of Famagusta. Yes. Tanks, tanks,
armored personnel, carriers, missile systems.
Yeah. No one has come officially to uh say this,
but um I've been fed this information and seen
footages. So, we're going to be caught right in
the middle of this. Yes, indeed. And where are
we going to escape? We're on an island. We're
going Yeah. Where are you going to run? Everybody
runs here. The place is the place is full of of,
you know, refugees and people sitting out war in
the region. Where would you run? There's nowhere
to run unless you go to Greece and Greece probably
is going to be involved anyway. So, what's your
projection? How is that going to happen? What?
How's America going to react? Are they going to
exit NATO? It depends on who's president. Donald
Trump hates NATO. He hates NATO. He wants the US
to withdraw from NATO. Um Donald Trump is only
going to be president for two and a half more
years. And I just can't imagine that an American
that there will ever be a with an American
withdrawal from NATO. The Americans are the kings
of NATO. Um although the Cypriot president said
last week that it was time for the European Union
to start thinking about a formal military alliance
in place of NATO just in case the Americans
withdraw. That's a very very smart thing to
do. You have to plan for every contingency.
Um if the Turks were to invoke Article 5,
that would be the end of NATO because there's no
way. Can you imagine Israel attacks Turkey? Turkey
invokes article 5. The United States is compelled
to attack Israel. Compelled by treaty to attack
Israel. That will never happen in a million years.
NATO falls apart. And then NATO falls apart. So,
I mean, it's kind of the goal of a lot of
NATO countries anyway, to get Turkey out
of the alliance. An EU military alliance would
be the next best thing, and it wouldn't include
Turkey. Yeah. But you're right, Cyprus is stuck
in the middle. So what happens? Do the European
Union countries rally to the side of of Israel? Do
they rally to the side of Turkey? What would their
militaries do if they're still in NATO? God help
us all. It's it's the beginning of World War II.
It really is while the Chinese and the Russians
sit back like this and enjoy the show. Yeah. There
was a pick up the pieces. There's a satirical
newspaper in the United States called The Onion.
Very funny. They had a headline the other day
and it said, "China, Russia content to sit by
and watch America destroy itself." That's what's
happening. And that's what's happening. John,
thank you for this first part of the conversation.
And to everyone watching, if you found this uh
discussion um insightful and valuable, uh please
uh like, share, subscribe, tap the notification
bell because you're helping this small channel
from the Eastern Mediterranean uh push through
the algorithm and reach out to more of you in the
US. We're very thankful for our 11,000 followers
on YouTube. Um I think it's tw 13,000 on X and
uh 6 and a half thousand on Tik Tok. But we need
another big push. So, we're counting on that. And
uh John, before I I want to thank you truly for
this first part of the conversation. But we before
we close, just a final ask. I'd love to ask you
what's your take on the channel and the kind of
work that we're doing here. Oh, this is my third
or fourth time on the on the show. Something like
that. Fourth. Fourth time. And I come on the show
because I believe in it. Uh, not only are you the
only um womanhosted political discussion podcast
in the Eastern Mediterranean and the Middle East,
you're the biggest and this is an outlet that
people need to pay attention to because you're
sitting right in the center of of a major global
conflict right now. And so I think people really
should listen, it doesn't cost anything to like
and subscribe. Nothing. And if you really want
to stay up on what is happening in the Eastern
Mediterranean, this is the place to find out.
Thank you for that, John. Thanks. My pleasure.
[music]